<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anant's-Blog</title>
    <description>I like to code while eating noodles</description>
    <link>http://localhost:8000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <author>
      <name>Anant Kumar</name>
      <email>anantk29082001@gmail.com</email>
      <uri>https://github.com/Anantk2908</uri>
    </author>
    
      <item>
        <title>amFoss Tasks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There were multiple languages used in the tasks.I didn’t know most of them but a little bit of googling and Youtube were a lot of help to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tasks-completed&quot;&gt;Tasks Completed:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Star Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeforces and Hackerrank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby Scraper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get it using Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CLI app using Golang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rusted Email&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Captcha Breaking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website Setup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Pong Game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python Source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project Euler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bandit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;0-installing-ubuntu&quot;&gt;0. Installing Ubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/home/anant/Desktop/photos/ubuntu.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were supposed to install ubuntu it was pretty straightforward but the encryption on the SSD was minor barrier as I had hard time disabling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-star-me&quot;&gt;1. Star Me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were supposed to star the amfoss repositories.To help us for the task we were given a script for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned the console in the inspect element of our browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-codeforces-and-hackkerank&quot;&gt;2. Codeforces and Hackkerank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This task got me more familiar to the python syntax as some of them required lists etc.Some of them also required maths logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about different type of errors you get while solving such question.Most common error while submitting was the runtime error which sometimes required me to re-think my logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-ruby-scraper&quot;&gt;3. Ruby Scraper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This task was about scraping the google search result and showing them.So for this task we required some ruby “gems”(which was essentially libraries in python).So I gem installed all the gems individually to later learning that you can install all of them by using a GEMFILE.The gems I used for the task was nokogiri,byebug,HTTParty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about ruby syntax.The byebug gem was also an helpful gem as it helped in quickly finding the CSS element required to scrape google&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-get-it-using-javascript&quot;&gt;4. Get it using javascript&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were required to fetch the information of a github user by taking username as input we were required to make a html page for the same.This task was the hardest as graphql being a new api there was nothing about it except the official documentation.The main thing was making the query as it is a query language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about graphql and getelementbyid in html.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-cli-app-using-golang&quot;&gt;5. CLI app using Golang&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were to make CLI app using go.In this the task the hardest part was for me to learn Golang specifically how to use API with it.The part to put the output in the text file was also a big problem for me as the twitter API gives you information in some unknown data type which was first to be converted to string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about Golang and the twitter API usage in Golang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-rusted-email&quot;&gt;6. Rusted Email&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were supposed to tell if the the email entered was valid or not using regex.Firstly I had to understand what regex was which was aided by youtube tutorials.The string input part was also hard to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about the basic syntax of rust,also about regex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-captcha-breaking&quot;&gt;7. Captcha Breaking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were supposed to extract basic text from an image.So for this task I thought of using the computer vision library but stumbled on the tesseract while researching on it.Tesseract ocr is basically the result of a well trained machine learning algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about tesseract ocr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-website-setup&quot;&gt;8. Website Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we are asked to make our own website(like this one) which required me to learn about jekyll templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this task I learned about how to edit the template to user parameters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;9-pong-game&quot;&gt;9. Pong Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were supposed to make webpage with pong game.So for this task I had to learn about basic javascript for detecting the mouse position in html.The only problem the game is singleplayer due to its mouse as input nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Improved my html a little more also learned about mouse input in javascript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-python-source&quot;&gt;10. Python Source&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this task we were given a encoding program we are supposed to make a python script which decodes the hash we are given.The hardest part in the program was understanding the xor function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I learned xor(Exclusive OR) also learned about various inbuilt functions like hex()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11-project-euler&quot;&gt;11. Project Euler&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has questions which are required to be solved using programming languages.The difficulty level was increasing per question by 4th and 5th question.I was getting errors so ended up on skipping those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Strengthened my Python programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;12-bandit&quot;&gt;12. Bandit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were questions which required us to find passwords using linux commands some of them were taught in our class but commands like ssh etc. were taught to me by google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learned about linux commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Anantk2908/amfoss-tasks&quot;&gt;Check out the repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:8000//Yet-Another-Sample-Page</link>
        <link href="http://localhost:8000/Yet-Another-Sample-Page"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:8000/Yet-Another-Sample-Page</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
